A couple months ago, I interviewed one of
the biggest business owners out in Los Angeles.
Excuse me, sir. Quick question for
you, man. Is this your Ferrari?
Yeah.
And what do you do for living out in
Los Angeles to be able to afford a Ferrari?
I own my own consulting firm.
So you're a business owner?
Yeah.
And how long have you been an entrepreneur for?
Six years.
And over these six years, what's been the most amount
of money that you've ever made in a single year?
Just over about $7.1 million last year.
$7 million?
Yeah.
You're sitting in a Ferrari right now.
This is a lot of people's dream car.
Tell me the story of how you bought this thing.
I'll be honest with you. I had
already offsetted all my taxes for the year,
and I just wanted a Christmas gift. So
I just went and bought myself a Ferrari cash.
When you don't pay taxes, a lot of these
types of purchases start to become a little bit different.
So you don't pay taxes?
Oh, no. I don't pay any taxes.
That video got over 60 million views across social media.
And like he said, he made over $7 million in
a single year and didn't pay any money in taxes.
That's Carlton Dennis.
And he invited us out to his house out in Los Angeles to give
you guys the game on what it takes to make a lot of money,
but more importantly, keep a lot of money and not have
to pay thousands of dollars or millions of dollars in taxes.
at the end of every year.
So let's go link up with Carlton and go
see what he has to say for you guys.
He's got the G-Wagon out front, a Lamborghini truck.
We got to go get this
game from him. Come on, you guys.
Carlton, what's going on, man?
How are you?
How you doing?
Good to see you.
Great to see you. Thank
you for having us out here.
Welcome to Orange County, man.
Seriously, man.
The last time I saw you, man,
our video did 60 million views together.
60 million?
60 million.
Are you serious?
48 million on Instagram.
Another 50 million.
Another 50 million on TikTok
and however million on Facebook, man.
Changing lives.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
I'm super happy to be out here, man.
I'm glad to have you out here.
We talked about it in the preview.
Yeah.
People saw the interview.
Yes.
You made how much money this last year?
All right.
I made 7.1 last year in 2023.
2024, we just crossed 11 and a half million.
And how much money did you pay
in taxes for those that don't know?
Last year, I paid $0 in
federal taxes, $26,000 in state taxes.
And this year in 2024, I'm on
pace to pay less than $92,000 in total.
Taxes.
Now, how the hell was this possible, man?
Because that's insane.
You're touching eight figures, high seven figures in a
single year, and you're not paying anything in taxes.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah.
How am I doing this?
Okay, so.
First of all, is that legal?
Everything I'm doing is legal.
So if the IRS wanted to come after you.
I welcome them.
IRS, you know who Carlton Dennis is.
I have one of the
largest YouTube channels for tax strategy.
The IRS knows who I am.
I'm not afraid of the IRS.
I'm not afraid to use
the tax code against the IRS.
And everything that I do is by the book, which
is why I have so much fun with the tax.
Okay.
I focus on income shifting strategies.
How do I take money off of my tax returns?
I focus on depreciation.
How do I create a paper
loss by investing in real estate?
And most importantly, I'm philanthropic.
I have a private family foundation that gives
money back to other charities outside of my own.
That allows for me to also reduce my tax bill.
These are the three things that I do every single
year that keep me at 0% on the federal side.
And I do pay a little bit of
that Cali tax, but I'm okay with it.
Yeah.
So I got to say this though, because I want
to put this in perspective for everyone watching right now.
Yeah.
Some of your clients are some of the biggest business.
Owners in the world.
And I've interviewed guys.
A lot of the people I've interviewed are his clients.
So, you know, this stuff better than anybody else.
And my goal for this video is to be a masterclass
for anybody watching to understand the ins and outs to the loopholes,
to being able to avoid these taxes.
Yes.
Right.
Because as you know it, the biggest
expense for most business owners is what?
Their taxes, man.
It's always the taxes, not
your mortgage, not your car payment.
It's not your payroll.
It's your taxes.
Have you seen people go broke with big tax bills?
I have seen people go broke with a big tax bill because they
spend more money than what they have left over to pay Uncle Sam.
And by the time that they
get the check from Uncle Sam,
they don't have a lot of money left over.
They don't have enough money in
their bank account to pay it.
Wow.
So let's get right into it.
What are some of the industries that you've invested in personally that's been able to
allow you to alleviate that bill and not have to pay anything to offset that?
It depends on the type of income that you're earning.
If you're a full-time W-2 or 1099 taxpayer, highly recommend that you look at short-term
rentals because the IRS will allow for you to manage the short-term rental for 100 hours.
And it becomes an active business.
If your tenants are staying in the property seven days or less, you can perform
a strategy called the cost segregation study, which forces a paper loss on the tax returns.
And that paper loss is what can.
Offset somebody's W-2 or somebody's 1099 income.
If you're somebody that maybe has a spouse that's not working, maybe it's
like a husband that's working in the wife's home taking care of the kids.
This is a perfect situation where you
can make your wife a real estate professional.
She manages over the real estate portfolio and you can
then make the real estate portfolio an active real estate business.
If you perform the cost segregation study strategy,
it creates a large tax deduction on the paper.
And then that paper tax deduction can
offset your W-2 or your 1099 income.
Now, I can speak for
a lot of entrepreneurs this year.
Our company will do this our
first year that we're doing seven figures.
Congratulations.
Thank you, my friend.
A 22.
Not too bad for 22.
Not at all.
I wanted to ask, though, right, because most people that get into business, they don't realize the insane amount that you
are going to have to pay in taxes if you're not smart about having a strategy to kind of avoid that.
So let's talk to the
people that are just starting out.
Maybe let's say that they're making their first six figures.
They're making $100,000 this year.
Yes.
And they maybe they didn't run
super lean where they had some expenses.
They didn't have great margins.
Yeah.
And they can't afford to.
And they're doing their business
pay insane amounts in taxes.
Yeah.
We see this a lot.
Yes.
Especially for people that are just starting
to kind of make a lot more money.
Six figures, seven figures.
Yeah.
What are some of those initial steps that people should
take to, again, avoid having to pay these crazy burdens?
And maybe if they don't have the means to be able to start investing in real estate, are there any other things
that people can do to be able to avoid having to pay crazy tax bills to save a lot more of that money?
Yeah.
The first thing that you want to do as a self-employed individual
that's starting to come into some money is look at your entity structuring.
Most self-employed individuals start out
as sole proprietorships or single member.
And that's great until you cross about $50,000 to $60,000.
Once you're across that point, you need to look at
switching to an S corporation to avoid paying self-employment taxes.
It's this nasty 15.3% on all of your business's profits.
If you just switch to an S
corporation, you can give yourself a salary now.
And now you only pay that 15.3%
on whatever you took out of your business.
You completely avoid 15.3% on
the rest of your business's profits.
That's step number one, entity structuring.
Step number two is let's figure out, did you take
advantage of all the things that you spent your money on?
Because sometimes business owners spend money on
things that they didn't know were write-offs.
And so we can allocate expenses that we're taking on the personal card over to
business if you forgot or didn't know that something was supposed to be a business write-off.
This can include cell phones, laptops, travel that should
have been business travel that you thought was personal.
We can allocate those expenses over to
your business to drop down that total liability.
Wow.
What's the biggest difference you notice in people's
approach to taxes from middle class versus wealthy people?
Speed.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed.
When you're wealthy, you're asking me, Carlton,
where do I move the money to?
When do we set up the foundation?
Where do I send the wire?
It happens in hours, not days, not weeks.
When I'm dealing with middle class, they're nervous.
They're analysis paralysis.
They want to do more
research than the tax professional did.
And it comes down to the fact that they're
scared to spend money in order to save money.
Wealthy people understand I have to spend money in order to
continue to play this game that Uncle Sam wants me to play.
And so they're willing to invest money
into different vehicles quickly to avoid taxes,
whereas the person that's in the middle
class is more attached to the money.
And will take their time to determine if they're
going to make an investment to offset their taxes,
which could end up leading to them being
in a situation where they just end up paying.
How much money have you saved your clients in taxes?
If you had to estimate, give me a number,
how much money have you saved your clients in taxes?
Well over $100 million.
Do you have a specific scenario or example of a
client that you've worked with where they were coming to you,
stressing about how to pay crazy taxes?
You don't have to say the person,
but could you give me a scenario?
We had a scenario of a
woman who came into the office.
This was previous to the pandemic where we
used to meet with people face to face.
And she was like, I'm
going to pay you $100 million.
She had an IRS audit where she
had taken a vehicle on her tax returns.
She had already visited seven other CPA firms.
They said that they didn't want to work with her.
When she came in, I looked at
her tax returns and I saw the notice.
They were disallowing a vehicle on her
tax returns in the amount of $1 million.
I asked her what the vehicle was.
She told me it was a yacht.
I said, why would we purchase a yacht for business?
She said, I am a real estate agent.
I speak on TV, million dollar listings.
And I like to show my athletes and entertainers
what it would look like to purchase a house
from the views of the O.C.
and the people who are watching this.
I log all of the time that
I go on and off of the boat.
I have a captain that knows every single
person that's come on and off the boat.
And I've documented everything.
By taking her captain's log booklet, some of the photos
that she had, as well as the expenses from her P&L,
we went into the audit and leveraging code section 162A,
which states that a business owner can take
a business deduction if the business deduction is ordinary,
necessary, and reasonable to the business
owner in the pursuit of income,
we should be able to take the right off.
We won that audit in less than an hour.
And that was her ability to
be able to write off a yacht.
So when I have clients coming to me stressed
out, sometimes it's stress around a one million dollar yacht.
Sometimes it's stress around a $50,000 tax bill.
But it's up to me to
figure out how to mitigate it.
Now, when I interviewed you out in Los
Angeles the last time, you were in a Ferrari.
Yes.
And I know you also got the G-Wagon.
You've got the Lamborghini Yuris.
Are they here today?
Yeah, those are outside.
Can we go take a look at them real quick?
Let's go take a look.
We might be picking up a new whip today, actually.
What are you going to be picking up?
So my Ferrari is in the shop right now.
And they called me and they're like, hey, we
have another Ferrari or we have this Lamborghini SV.
Which one would you like?
Which one would you like more?
I was like, I don't know.
I kind of have a Lamborghini, but
I'll come down and test drive the SV.
And I went down and test drove the Lamborghini SV.
And I think we might
be picking the Lamborghini up soon.
Yeah.
Now, what's crazy is most people look
at cars like this as the depreciating assets.
How do you feel about that perspective that
people give you whenever they say that about cars?
Cars are depreciating assets.
I 100% agree with them.
But I also took 100% bonus depreciation on this car,
which saved me, I don't know, about $92,000 in taxes.
That $92,000.
That's a lot.
$92,000 got reinvested into a multifamily property in Texas.
That's paying me cash flow of about $1,400 a month.
So if you're somebody that knows how to do math, you can buy a vehicle like this, offset your taxes, reinvest the tax savings into a cash flow
producing asset and not worry about the fact that this car is still losing value sitting here in the driveway because it losing value offset in my taxes.
Right.
So the G Wagon right here,
why is it eligible for that deduction?
Is it because of the size
and the weight of it or?
Yeah.
So with this G Wagon, the gross
vehicle weight ratio is over 6,000 pounds.
And if you have a vehicle where the
gross vehicle weight ratio is over 6,000 pounds,
plus the vehicle is being
used more than 50% for business,
the IRS will allow for you
to take the vehicle's purchase price
and write it off on your tax returns
under Code Section 179 plus Code Section 168K.
So I utilized this strategy in 2022 on this
vehicle right before bonus depreciation went to 80% in 2023.
We're here in 2024. Bonus depreciation is at 60%.
Donald Trump just got elected president.
He's expected to get inaugurated here
in the next couple of weeks.
There's a possibility that bonus
depreciation could go back to 100%.
And as a tax professional,
I'm waiting to hear about that.
Now, a couple months ago, I actually
interviewed a lady out in Beverly Hills,
and she was coming out of a G-Wagon.
I asked her what she did
or how much money she made,
and she let's just say at
least 10 times what a G-Wagon is.
And the reason why I'm asking this is, and
I want to talk about business here for a second.
What does it take? This is a lot of
people's dream car, and you've got a lot of them.
But let's just take the G-Wagon, for example, 100, 200,000,
sometimes more than 200,000.
Even that for this car.
A lot of people dream to be
able to afford a car like this.
How can somebody get a G-Wagon in today's world?
You can buy one of
these cars if you understand leverage.
As a business owner, I wasn't
going to buy a car like this
if I didn't get some type of
benefit tax-wise, money coming back into my pocket.
Here's an example.
Let's just say that you're a
business owner that's making $200,000 a year.
You could put down a $20,000
down payment on a car like this
and be able to write off the
entire purchase price, which was about 200K.
If you have 200K of income,
and you have a $200,000,
write-off on your tax returns,
you're essentially tax-free.
Someone that has $200,000 of reportable
income may pay $50,000 in taxes.
So they're pocketing 50K and then put $20,000 down.
They have a delta of about 30K.
Now they can reinvest
that 30K into cashflow-producing assets
or back into their business that
can help them make more money.
For somebody that's going to buy a car like this,
I would highly recommend that you do so with leverage.
You brought up leverage.
There's a big debate in business.
Good debt versus bad debt.
What's your thoughts on debt as a business owner?
Yes, there's good debt and there's bad debt.
There's bad debt, which is consumer debt,
credit card debt, high interest rate debt.
That's the type of debt you want to avoid.
And then there's good debt, which is debt
in the form of loans, like buying a house.
The reason why that is considered good debt
is because you're parking your money into
an asset that could appreciate over time,
and you have the ability to borrow against the property.
The reason why I love real estate is because
I can take out cash out refinances or HELOCs,
which means that even though I put my
money into a property and I took out leverage,
I may be able to pull out
more than what I put into the property
and I can take out more
than what I put into the property.
And that's why I love leverage.
And that's why I love real estate.
Many wealthy entrepreneurs have built their wealth by reinvesting
into real estate over and over and over again.
And God forbid something happens to
them, their heirs pick up those properties.
But sometimes they pick up those
properties with no debt on the deal.
And so when you think about it, the person that was
living leveraged debt to build up this entire real estate portfolio
and then passes it off to their
heirs, sometimes without any debt on the deal.
So some of the wealthiest
families got wealthy because of debt.
Yeah, I have a client out in Miami
owns several hundred million dollars worth of real estate.
And he actually said that you can tell how wealthy someone
is based on the amount of access to debt that they have,
how much debt they're able to
kind of pull out, which is fascinating.
It's really interesting to be.
Yeah, the more debt I take on, the
more I'm actually able to increase my buying power,
because if I'm able to keep more of my hard earned
money in my pocket and not overextend myself while I'm leveraging debt,
I can continue to increase my buying power because I'll
be able to continue to take on more and more debt,
but go into business.
And so I think that's the biggest
thing that I've learned about the bank.
I think that's the biggest thing that I've learned about the bank
is that you can actually get bigger and bigger investments because of it.
What's the best way to kind of get access to that capital, that credit lines
in today's world that you've seen has been efficient for yourself or other people as well?
The best way to get access to credit is to use
credit and to start establishing the right type of relationships with bankers.
I know that for me, it was getting into
the banks and actually having a relationship with a banker.
And then after having a certain amount
of deposits, then you earn a private banker.
Once you have a private banking relationship,
you're going to have a lot of people
that will start to get into your bankers.
So if you're in the bank, you're going to have a
lot of people that will start to get into your bankers.
I think if you don't want to, to pull out money,
if you need transfers, you don't have to pay for the transfers.
You don't have to pay for the wires.
And most importantly, they understand your
business because they're a partner with you.
So if you need access to debt,
they understand what you're using the debt for,
because they have a pretty good
understanding of what your business model is.
Let's say someone is making $100,000 a year right now.
Do you have any specific strategies they
can implement like kind of a walkthrough,
a blueprint on what they can do to
be able to avoid paying crazy money in taxes?
You want me to do a walkthrough right now?
All right. So we said a hundred K, right? Yes.
And this could be a hundred K W2, 1099 entrepreneur,
entrepreneur. Okay. It's a hundred K. Now let's just
say that I want to use a rental property
to offset my taxes. I'm going to have to come
up with a down payment, but here's what I could do.
Let's just say that this property is $500,000 and
I had a separate hundred thousand dollars that I
saved up. So I'm going to take out a
$400,000 loan. I could buy this hundred thousand dollar
property. I just need one property. And what I'm
going to do is I'm going to list this property
as a short term rental. Here's the reason why,
if I list this property as a short term rental,
and if this property has tenants that stay in
the property seven days or less, and I manage
the property for a hundred hours, I can
perform a strategy on this property called the cost
segregation study. Now this property right here is
worth 500 K, but with a cost segregation study,
I can accelerate depreciation on average. When performing a
cost segregation study, I can accelerate
depreciation on average. When performing a
segregation study you can get 20 of the building's
purchase price as a year one tax write-off so with
five hundred thousand dollar property twenty percent
of that would equal a hundred thousand
dollars if i had a hundred thousand dollars w-2
income and i had a hundred thousand dollar loss
on my tax returns from depreciation i'm tax free
and this is how somebody can take a five hundred
thousand dollar property convert it to a short-term rental
manage it create a paper loss and offset a
hundred percent of their w-2 or 299 income and
this is just with an example of someone making
100k imagine if there's somebody that's making a
million and we took this property to a million
dollars or to two million dollars this game becomes
so fun and that's why i need debt right
because in order to buy this property i may not
have 500k saved up but i may have 100k saved up
and i'm going to take out leverage opm to get
that other 400k people's money all day i've said it
before i'll say it again you know they don't
teach that in school right absolutely not bro this game
of building wealth and buying real estate is not
taught in schools i got to ask you a question
you're going to ask me a question i'm going to
ask you a question you're going to ask me a question
ask you for one more what is a tax hack
somebody watching this right now can take with them into
their business their personal income that they can
apply give them one more tax hack right now
that is not taught that most people do not
know most people don't know what the augusta rule is
and it's funny how the augusta rule came to
be it was a golf tournament called the masters golf
tournament that was it's held every single year
in augusta georgia the issue with augusta georgia is
there's not enough hotels out there so homeowners
had to open up their primary residences to
travelers who are coming in to watch
this golf tournament people have been watching tire
woods play at the masters tournament for years the
city of augusta georgia enacted a code that said
if you rent out your property for 14 days or
less you don't have to pay taxes on the rental income
in the state of georgia it's funny because a year
and a half later it became a federal tax code irc-280a
now anybody whether you're a business owner or not
can rent out your primary residence for 14 days
charge rent and not pay taxes on the first 14
days of rental income this has been a strategy we've
utilized with business owners and we've been using
this strategy for a long time and we've been
using it for a long time and we've been using it for
a long time and we've been using it for a long time
because if you have an s corp the s corp
is considered a separate person from who you are so
you as a business owner who owns the s
corp can rent your primary residence to your s corporation
for 14 days charge rent and deduct it on
your tax returns and it's like a tax-free distribution
coming right back to you the individual definitely
a strategy that most taxpayers are not implementing
but is so easy and is low-hanging fruit
and i absolutely recommend you get it implemented that's
straight game right there for everybody that's
watching where can everybody find you at right
now yeah you guys can find our company on
our website at the link in the description box below
and if you want to get a free assessment of
any of our tax questions please go to our website at
taxalchemy.com visit our youtube channel at carlton dennis
and go on instagram and send us a
message if you have any tax questions we'd be
more than happy to provide a free assessment amazing
guys the links to connect with carlton check them
out are down in the description below go check out
his business go connect with carlton thank you so
much for having us thank you this was exceptional
the game was crazy my
friend let's go thank you brother